Guide to the Marie Hansen Taylor Papers, 1848-1927
Department of Special Collections
Marie Hansen Taylor Papers,
1848-1927
Special Collections M0603
Taylor, Marie Hansen, 1829-1925
4 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of the great-grandaughter, Natalie Kiliani Shastid, 1992
Biography
Born in Gotha, Germany. Her father was the court astronomer. Married Bayard Taylor, writer, traveller, and artist, in 1856. She knew many of the authors and publishers of her time. She collected recipes with her daughter in anticipation of doing a cookbook. The plan was to include with the recipes a bit about their history. Their daughter, Lillian, married Dr. Otto Theobold Kiliani.
Scope and Content
Writings of Marie Taylor, 1848 and 1854 (poetry and prose). 19 journals of Marie Taylor, 1860-1877; 1 of Lillian Taylor Kiliani, 1919. Correspondence between the family, 1891-1927. There are also 4 boxes of cookbook material, much handwritten in both German and English.
Access terms
Taylor, Bayard, 1825-1878.; Kiliani, Lillian Bayard Taylor, 1858.; Kiliani, Otto Theobald.; American literature--19th century.; Cookery.; United States--Social life and customs.
Container List
- Correspondence: April 4, 1891 - Oct. 4, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: Oct. 6, 1891 - April 20, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: May 20, 1892 - Nov. 1, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Dec. 9, 1892 - Dec. 9, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: Feb. 21, 1895 - Aug. 13, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: Dec. 13, 1899 - Nov. 4, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: Oct. 24, 1905 - June 26, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence: Aug. 16, 1912 - June 30, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: Aug. 9, 1915 - Oct. 15, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence: Nov. 14, 1915 - Nov. 11, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence: Oct. 22, 1917 - Sept. 10, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Reminiscence of stay in San Gemini, Italy, by Marie Taylor 1858 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Journals: 1848 book of verse by Marie Taylor; personal journals1860 -1867 (Box 2)
- Journals: 1868, 1870 - 1875, 1877 personal journals; 1919 personal journal: Lillian T. Kiliani (Box 3)
- Cookbook Material: clippings, recipes (Box 4-6)
- Oversized Materials (Box 7)